<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>slashlog</title>
    <link href="https://slashlog.org/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://slashlog.org" />
    <updated>2019-03-08T22:48:20+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>marvin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://slashlog.org</id>

    <entry>
        <title>bashblog</title>
        <author>
            <name>marvin</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://slashlog.org/bashblog/"/>
        <id>https://slashlog.org/bashblog/</id>

        <updated>2019-03-08T22:40:05+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    bashblog is a static blog generator, link list and knowledge base. It solves a simple problem: How to preserve the thought or a summary of an article or video. bashblog receives links and videos via email and stores a text connected to it. This way an article and the gained knowledge keeps its value. Share via mail is available on every platform, in every app and tool. E-mail is lightweight and works everywhere, even in the subway. By storing whole sentences it becomes searchable and even indexable by Google. bashblog started as a simple script, but by publishing it to GitHub, it thought me much more than scripting.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>bashblog is a static blog generator, link list and knowledge base.<br>It solves a simple problem: How to preserve the thought or a summary of an article or video.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img src="https://slashlog.org/media/posts/1/demo.png" alt="bashblog screenshot" width="1042" height="653">
<figcaption >bashblog screenshot</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>bashblog receives links and videos via email and stores a text connected to it. This way an article and the gained knowledge keeps its value.</p>
<div class="callout callout-primary">
<div>
<p class="msg msg--info"><em>Share via mail is available on every platform, in every app and tool.</em></p>
<p><em>E-mail is lightweight and works everywhere, even in the subway.</em></p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight  msg--info">By storing whole sentences it becomes searchable and even indexable by Google.</p>
<p>bashblog started as a simple script, but by <a href="https://github.com/6uhrmittag/bashblog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">publishing it to GitHub</a>, it thought me much more than scripting.</p>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
